Qingan Yan

Office 2900 Lakeside Dr, Suite 230 Email yanqinganssg@gmail.com

Santa Clara, California, USA, 95054 qingan.yan@jd.com

Homepage https://yanqingan.github.io **Mobile Phone** +1(669)-258-9935

Short Bio

I am a computer vision scientist at JD.com Silicon Valley Research Center in Santa Clara, California. Before that, I received my Ph.D. degree in Computer Science from Wuhan University, China, in 2017.

My work focus on the field of computer vision and AR/VR. In particular, I tackle the challenges in 3D reconstruction, SLAM, image and RGBD data analysis. I am also interested in the application of deep learning within 3D field, such as semantic shape understanding and scene recovery.

Work Experience

• JD.com Silicon Valley Research Center, Santa Clara, USA Nov 2017 – current

Position: Research Engineer

<u>Duty:</u> Design efficient algorithms for JD.com's AR&AI products using 3D vision and deep learning technologies.

• Wuhan University, Wuhan, China Jul 2015 – Jul 2017

Position: Research Assistant

Duty: Conduct research on scene understanding and 3D reconstruction.

• CIS Academic Summer Session, Wuhan, China Jul 2016 – Aug 2016

Position: *Teaching Assistant*

Duty: Responsible for assigning tests and advising projects with Prof. Brian A. Barsky, UC Berkeley, USA

• Wuhan EONES technology Co.,Ltd, Wuhan, China Jul 2008 – Apr 2009

Position: Software Engineer

Duty: Develop logistics management systems and GIS systems.

Education

• Ph.D. in Computer Science, **Wuhan University**, China Sep 2012 – Jul 2017

Advisor: Prof. Chunxia Xiao

Areas of Focus: Computer Vision, Computer Graphics

• M.S. in Computer Science, **Southwest University of Science and Technology** Sep 2009 – Jun 2012

Advisor: Prof. Yadong Wu

Areas of Focus: Computer Vision, Image Processing, Human-Computer Interaction

• B.E. in Computer Science, **Hubei University for Nationalities**, China Sep 2004 – Jun 2008

Areas of Focus: Image Processing

Publications

- Qingan Yan, Long Yang, Ling Zhang, Chunxia Xiao. *Distinguishing the indistinguishable: exploring structural ambiguities via geodesic context.* IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2017, 3836-3844. (Spotlight presentation)
- Ling Zhang, Qingan Yan, Zheng Liu, Hua Zou and Chunxia Xiao. *Illumination Decomposition for Photograph with Multiple Light Sources.* IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP), 2017, 26(9): 4114-4127.

- Long Yang, **Qingan Yan**, Yanping Fu, Chunxia Xiao. *Surface reconstruction via fusing sparse-sequence of depth images*. **IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG). (To appear in 2017)**
- Long Yang, **Qingan Yan** and Chunxia Xiao. *Shape-controllable geometry completion for point cloud models.* **The Visual Computer (TVC), 2017, 33(3): 385-398.**
- Qingan Yan, Long Yang, Chao Liang, Huajun Liu, Ruimin Hu and Chunxia Xiao. *Geometrically based linear iterative clustering for quantitative feature correspondence*. Computer Graphics Forum (CGF), 2016, 35(7): 1-10. (Proceedings of Pacific Graphics 2016, Oral presentation)
- Qingan Yan, Zhan Xu and Chunxia Xiao. Fast feature-oriented visual connection for large image collections. Computer Graphics Forum (CGF), 2014, 33(7): 339-348. (Proceedings of Pacific Graphics 2014, Oral presentation)
- Yadong Wu **Qingan Yan**, Jie Fu, Hongli Deng and Lili Song. *Vision based multi-touch system used in visualization*. **IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (PacificVis), 2011. (Poster presentation)**

Patents

• Yadong Wu, **Qingan Yan**, Zhiqin Liu. *Optical multi-touch contact detection based on visual attention model (in Chinese)*. **Patent Number: CN102855025B, granted, June.17.2015**.

Selected Projects

- Multi-modal Sensing based Outdoor Structures Reconstruction and Editing Jan 2016 Jul 2017 <u>Description:</u> Developing innovative approaches for modeling outdoor architectural structures combining multi-modal sensor data, such as Internet imagery, aerial photography and depth cameras. We also explore deep learning methods to transfer the style of different architectures.
- Editing and Storytelling in Unstructured Video Collections

 Jan 2015 Jul 2017

 <u>Description:</u> Collected a new dataset of faces and outdoor scenes. We use this data to train a CNN to predict the aging of human faces and the temporal change of natural scenes. We also explore the potentiality of other image analytics in deep learning.
- Crowdsourced 3D Streetscape Reconstruction and Augmentation

 Jan 2013 Dec 2016

 Description: Built an unstructured imagery reconstruction framework that addresses several relevant and challenging problems existing in recent structure from motion modeling techniques, such as the matching of image collections, desification of feature correspondences and disambiguation of duplicate scenes.
- Vision based Finger-touch Interaction

 Sep 2010 May 2012

 Description: Developed a vision based multi-touch system which requires lasers to be the light source and utilizes a camera to detect bright touching points. We also designed a remote finger-control system that combines Kinect and Internet of Things
- Digital Image Super-resolution
 Oct 2009 Oct 2010

 Description: Developed a novel algorithm which allows rendering more vivid frames efficiently on television chip.

Honors and Awards

- The Second Class Graduate Academic Innovation Award of Wuhan University, 2017.
- Travel Grant Award from CVPR Doctoral Consortium, 2017.
- Excellent Graduate Award of Southwest University of Science and Technology, 2012.
- The First Class Scholarship of Jiangsu Yangshan, 2011.
- Outstanding Student Award of Southwest University of Science and Technology, 2010-2011.
- The Second Class Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis Award of Hubei Province, 2008.
- Excellent Graduate Award of Hubei University for Nationalities, 2008.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Development Libraries: Other Tools: C/C++, Matlab, Python

OpenGL, OpenCV, QT, OpenMPI, Caffe, Tensorflow, PCL, CUDA, unity, D3.js ETEX, Ubuntu, Git, Kinect, Orbbec